You two, please wait here.
Listen, don't move
until you get the signal.
Even if our comrades are cut down.
Your mission
is to take Niimi's head
the moment the enemy falters.
Soji.
Yes?
Sorry, but he's mine to kill.
I'd say it's a fair game
for whoever can land the first strike.
But then again, I am the fastest one here,
so I'll probably get him.
- Don't you get so damn cocky.
- Yamanami.
Saito.
Position me here, too.
I told you to be on the front lines.
What difference does one man make?
That's not for you to decide.
There are ten of us against 150 of them.
Surely you understand
how much each man matters.
Please.
Saito.
What is it now?
Trying to hog the spotlight?
That's not it.
I'm the one
who has to kill Niimi.
- But--
- Yamanami.
On second thought,
I'd rather be on the front line.
Hijikata.
When it comes to a fight
it's no fun
unless you're leading the charge.
SONG OF THE SAMURAI
Drop dead, Niimi!
Why you...
You bastard!
Go!
Damn it! You're not getting away!
How dare a peon stare at me
while I'm down?
Is it that funny to see a man
groveling on the ground?
You really are a bastard
who has it coming.
Saito.
This is for Eisaburo.
Don't think you're getting an easy death.
You want to hear something funny?
It's about Abiru.
Don't you want to know how he died?
He was crying.
"I don't want to die!"
He was a sniveling, snot-nosed mess,
crying like a stuck pig as he wasted away!
Secret Sword. It's coated in poison!
I see.
So that's what it is.
So this is what you used to kill Eisaburo?
Did you provoke me to cut your finger
just to make me let my guard down?
Impossible. How?
When I saw Eisaburo's body,
I knew at first glance.
The wound wasn't deep enough to be fatal.
Yet he died in one strike.
That means one thing.
That your blade had
to be coated in poison.
You bastard!
You saw through me from the start?
Besides, if Eisaburo had
fought you head-on
there's no way he would've lost
to the likes of you!
I won.
I won!
Bye, you dumb runts!
I swear I'll make you pay for this!
You have a surprisingly short memory.
I'm sure I told you.
"Don't think you're getting
an easy death."
All right!
I lost!
So I'm begging you!
Look.
My fingers have been cut off.
My leg has been slashed.
With these injuries,
I'll never be able to hold a sword again.
Please, just spare my life!
Of course
considering everything I've done
I know it's selfish of me to ask!
That's why...
Is this enough for you to forgive me?
You want to live that badly?
You're truly pathetic.
Forget it.
Well, that killed the mood.
You mean it?
Yes. Just get lost.
I won.
You thought you won?!
Niimi Nishiki.
I was the only one who forgave you.
But the one
you really need forgiveness from
isn't here, unfortunately.
Go ask him for forgiveness yourself
in the afterlife.
Niimi Nishiki's betrayal
was never made public.
Instead, the cover story
was that he committed seppuku
for unauthorized fundraising.
Here, Eisaburo. I'm returning it to you.
Your brother's keepsake.
Now you can rest.
In the end, maybe he helped me beat Niimi.
But Hajime buddy...
"Hajime buddy"?
Don't you forget this.
Back there, I could've easily
taken the shot at Niimi myself.
But I saw what you wanted
so I reluctantly let you have him.
Listen up! You only got
to take Niimi down because of me!
Toshi, you're the same as ever,
saying something so stupid.
- What's so stupid about it?
- I almost have to respect it.
Hey, Eisaburo, are you watching this?
Toshi's an idiot, as always.
Hey, takes one to know one, you idiot.
- Right, Eisaburo?
- "Takes one to know one"? Me, an idiot?
Just watch and see who the real idiot is.
Just watch, Eisaburo!
- It's obviously Toshi!
- Hey, you!
Aijiro, I guess the next time we train
together will be in the afterlife.
Until then, keep an eye on me,
even though I'm talentless.
I see. So Niimi has fallen.
He was a tragic figure in his own way.
Explain yourself, Yamazaki.
You said Kondo's group
was less than ten men strong, right?
So how the hell did they beat Niimi
and his 150 men?
Winning and losing are a matter of luck.
That's not my department.
Niimi was your master, wasn't he?
Don't you feel any remorse?
Money!
Remorse?
You can't exactly eat remorse, can you?
You're rotten to the core.
Can't say I dislike it, though.
Money! I'll take that as a compliment.
So, what's our move, Master Serizawa?
Now, most of our men
will flock to their side.
Hirayama.
What I've always wanted
is an all-out war, no tricks. Got it?
Of course, I understand.
But...
We need more fuel for the fire. Yes.
Start.
Oh? Goro, you've gotten sloppy.
Ichiji! You bastard!
Niji, you're here, too?
What's with that look on your face?
You got a problem with us being here?
Yes, I do.
We're the guys
who raised hell in Mito, aren't we?
Okay, everyone is here.
So, Kamo. So, who's first?
You wouldn't have called us
unless it was for someone big, right?
I know. The shogun!
Whoa, you want to go after Lord Iemochi?
Still a dumbass, I see.
Ichiji, Goro just called me a dumbass!
Hey! The one who calls someone a dumbass
- is the real dumbass!
- Dumbass.
Goro, don't get too cocky.
You're supposed to be his right-hand man
so why hasn't Kamo
taken over the world yet?
See? Goro is the real dumbass!
Shut up, you dumbass.
Want me to crush you right here and now?
Come on! What a lively bunch.
The reason I called you here is simple.
The stage is finally set to my liking.
I intend to enjoy every last second of it.
You all get it, don't you?
What I'm getting at?
Unleash your overwhelming violence
and trample all over Kyo.
Awesome!
Here they come.
Serizawa Kamo is on the move.
He has gathered new allies
and appears to be plotting something.
What on earth is that man planning to do?
I have no idea whatsoever.
All we know is...
Please, go ahead.
Yamanami, who did you say that to?
The reason I called you here is simple.
I intend to enjoy every last second of it.
You all get it, don't you?
- What I'm getting at?
- This voice... Is it Kamo?
Unleash your overwhelming violence
and trample all over Kyo.
Yamazaki, you bastard!
I thought you were on Niimi's side.
He's not on anyone's side.
He'll do anything for the right price.
He's the one who spread that rumor for us
about Kondo and Lord Katamori's meeting.
So he's a double agent.
Something like that.
My loyalty lies with the highest bidder.
Playing both sides
for double the pay, huh?
You're a special kind of scumbag.
Why, thank you.
Serizawa Kamo wants a piece of us.
The real fight starts now.
- Oh, it's beautiful.
- It is beautiful.
At this time, another power was beginning
to make its mark on Kyo.
The Satsuma clan, a powerhouse
from western provinces, allied with Aizu.
What happened? Are you okay?
Are you okay?
Are you okay? Hey!
That haori jacket.
Are you with the Shinsengumi?
That accent.
They're from Satsuma, no doubt about it.
Yes.
What do you want?
You're with the Aizu clan!
And we of Satsuma and the Aizu are...
Less talking, more fighting,
or you'll end up dead.
You're blocking our patrol. Step aside!
I can't understand
a damn word he's saying.
Bunch of potato samurai.
What did you say?!
Goodness, the potato is angry.
I'm scared, Ichiji.
Bastard! Don't you dare insult Satsuma!
Get them! Cut them down!
Just what you'd expect from Satsuma.
So quick to fight. Saves us the trouble.
Niji, that's the Jigen style.
- Hiyah!
Scary.
So scary... Scary!
It's all right. Niji, you are capable.
Have some confidence.
Hiyah!
Kill, Niji!
Okay, I get it, Ichiji!
- Hiyah!
Hiyah!
That was so scary.
Jigen style? Piece of cake.
What's their deal?
Everyone, step back.
Ichiji, that guy's eyes are terrifying.
Who are you?
Why is the Shinsengumi attacking Satsuma?
Ichiji, his eyes are scary!
Too much trouble.
You don't have to answer.
Hanjiro! You aren't planning to do that...
Hanjiro?
SATSUMA RETAINER,
NAKAMURA HANJIRO
This is awesome!
I've been dying to see
the real thing! Right, Niji?
- You're right, Ichiji!
- Let's go!
Fall!
Ouch! Ichiji, he cut me!
Damn, what incredible power.
I see.
So you're Hanjiro the Manslayer, huh?
What? Is that right, Ichiji?
Even though it was two against one,
you actually landed a hit on me.
Who the hell are you guys?
Hey! Hurry! Over here!
It's the Shinsengumi!
Looks like we both cheated death today.
I swear, I'm going to kill both of you.
Let's get out of here, Niji.
- They are coming!
- Hey!
- Get them!
- After them!
Kyo sure is wild!
If more of them show up, we won't make it.
What do we do, Niji?
It was scary, but fun too, wasn't it?
- After them!
- Hey! Hold it!
- Get them! Hey!
- Get them!
Hey!
Wait.
I said, wait.
The perpetrators appear
to be from the Shinsengumi.
The Shinsengumi?
Yes, my lord.
Three men attacked Satsuma samurai,
reportedly wearing their striped haori.
I wondered how they would play this.
So this is how.
They may be allied with the Aizu clan
for now, but ultimately
Satsuma is still an outside domain.
Sooner or later,
they will turn against the shogunate.
What are your orders?
Kanbei.
Yes, my lord.
Relay this to Kamo and Kondo.
To settle this score
one of their heads will have to roll.
Yes, my lord! At once!
Well, hello there.
- Enjoy.
- Welcome, sir. Welcome.
Mr. Sagawa, your guest has arrived.
Yes.
What's the matter?
Missing the smell of face powder?
I can't believe you actually came.
I can't exactly say no
when Oume is the one asking.
Thanks for setting this up.
There isn't a soul here
who doesn't know about you two.
Did you never think I was gathering men
to capture Serizawa?
I've seen many men in my line of work
so I can read a man's true intentions
in his eyes.
Well, then, if you'll excuse me.
She's quite a woman, huh?
So, what do you want, Kanbei?
The Satsuma clan was attacked.
Over a dozen of their men were cut down,
and Nakamura Hanjiro was wounded, too.
Someone managed to wound
the great Hanjiro the Manslayer?
Vast though Kyo may be, the men with
that skill can be counted on one hand.
So you think I did it. Is that it?
Coming here to accuse me... You had better
be ready for the consequences.
Just kidding.
Still can't get a rise out of you, can I?
You're right on the money. Yes.
So it was you.
But why?
Now, we of Aizu have no choice
but to cut you down.
And that's not all. The Satsuma men
are coming at you full force.
Well, that's because
I engineered it that way.
I don't understand.
Why are you in such a rush to die?
Hey, Kanbei.
I've been wanting to ask
the greatest samurai in Japan something.
What is a samurai?
Of all the things to ask.
They serve their lord
with loyalty and martial prowess
and lay down their lives for their lord
without a second thought.
That is what it means to be a samurai.
Loyalty like that makes you a fool
in this day and age.
But listen.
Don't give me
that idealistic crap, Kanbei.
I'm sure you know it in your gut.
Ultimately, samurai are just thugs
who only know a life of violence.
So, let's bloom as wildly as we can
until we fall.
What is that bastard Kamo playing at?
Is he trying to take down
both Aizu and us?
Why would he be so reckless?
He just wants to fan the flames, right?
Well, I don't really care why.
I'm just here to deliver
an order from Lord Katamori.
To make amends for this,
we require the head of either Kondo
or Serizawa.
Why Kondo's head?
That bastard Kamo is the one who did it!
- This is insane!
- His Lordship knows full well.
Then why...
If we are defeated,
I will offer up my head.
Anything less will not
appease Satsuma's wrath.
Settle this, and quickly.
Soji.
Let's spar.
Kondo.
Soji.
You're not getting any funny ideas,
are you?
I can't fool you, can I, Kondo?
Hijikata won't like this, but...
I'll be the one to kill Serizawa.
- Soji.
- Don't worry, Kondo. I'll be fine.
I won't lose myself again.
Hey.
Hey, what's wrong? Why the long face?
Hey, Kamo.
What the hell are you doing here?
I had a feeling you were calling for me.
Don't screw with me!
What's got you so worked up?
Why did you attack Satsuma?
I thought you wanted to fight us!
You sold out Niimi for that, didn't you?
The bigger the fire, the better, right?
You make no sense as usual.
What? You really don't get it?
No, I don't.
You should understand
that urge to leap into a raging fire.
Don't give me that crap.
Unlike you
I won't abandon my comrades
and throw my life away.
Then why do you want to kill me?
For the Shinsengumi? For your comrades?
No, that's not it, is it?
Even you must see
where this era is headed.
The end of the samurai.
So, in an age like this,
why did you become a samurai?
Blood.
Yes.
Because fighting a strong opponent
makes my blood boil.
It's the only time I feel alive.
- I feel the same.
- Then draw.
I want to be stronger.
To think of nothing else,
to challenge opponents stronger than you
to reach greater heights with the sword.
That's the only way I can live, but...
What lies at the end of that path?
Death.
I've already made my peace with that.
The weak die.
That's all there is to it.
That's right. Exactly.
A man can't choose how he's born.
But he can decide how he dies.
That's why...
from the moment I was born,
I have sought only one thing.
That is, how I will meet my end.
Nothing more.
You've realized it too, haven't you?
You and I are two sides of the same coin.
We're light and shadow.
Men who only feel alive in battle.
It's no coincidence we met.
Our very souls are drawn to each other.
Dead of night. At Sumiya, in Shimabara.
Don't keep me waiting.
Bring it on.
Right now, Serizawa is...
at the Sumiya in Shimabara,
with his mistress, Oume.
That's correct, isn't it, Yamazaki?
- Yes.
- There you are.
In addition,
I have intel that Serizawa's men
plan to attack our headquarters tonight.
Their target is, of course
Kondo Isami's head.
Here is my plan.
We'll launch
a preemptive strike on Serizawa.
Toshi.
That's not it, Yamanami.
What exactly do you find wrong
with my plan?
I'm saying we don't need any damn schemes.
We're going to face them head-on.
That's it.
Honestly...
When will you ever
grow out of this foolishness?
This is...
a power struggle between the Kondo
and the Serizawa factions.
Do you even realize that?
This isn't a game!
You're the one who doesn't get it!
What did you just say?
This...
isn't just some power struggle.
Kamo is testing us.
To see which of us is a true samurai.
If we can't rise to that challenge...
then what's the point
of being a samurai at all?
You have no sense of your duty
as vice-commander!
Are you willing to destroy us all
just to satisfy your emotions?!
That's enough.
What Yamanami is saying is totally valid.
Still...
I'm with Toshi on this.
Kondo.
Is winning by scheming really a victory?
If we continue down that path
won't the Shinsengumi become
an empty shell of its ideals?
No, but--
In order for the Shinsengumi
to get stronger
we will crush this internal strife
openly and head-on.
And in doing so...
we'll make a statement
to our men and to the world.
So, please.
Yamanami.
Understood.
But...
on one condition.
Kondo stays here.
Should we fall in battle...
you will annihilate any enemy forces
that get through.
Do you agree?
Yes.
Understood.
Thank you.
I...
simply chose what I believe
is the best path in this situation.
- We move out in half an hour.
- Okay.
Vice-Commander Yamanami Keisuke
will be in command.
May fortune favor you all in battle!
- Sir!
OCTOBER 30, 1863
Shimabara, usually alive
with noise as evening falls
was shrouded in a deathly silence.
Tonight would be the final showdown.
A rumor to that effect was spreading,
though from where, no one knew.